I see it now.
I can't let you leave.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
I'm sorry too.
Poor Salo.
That isn't Jayce.
But there is another will
at work within him.
I thought I heard something
just before the portal closed.
Ancient, like a...
Like a voice.
This is a sophisticated conjuration.
A singularity,
simultaneously self-replicating
and self-annihilating.
We've never seen complexity like this.
Flawless...
exquisite...
chaos.
♪ I wake up to the sounds
Of the silence that allows ♪
♪ For my mind to run around
With my ear up to the ground ♪
♪ I'm searching to behold
The stories that are told ♪
♪ When my back is to the world
That was smiling when I turned ♪
♪ Tell you you're the greatest ♪
♪ But once you turn, they hate us ♪
♪ Oh, the misery ♪
♪ Everybody wants to be my enemy ♪
♪ Oh, spare the sympathy ♪
♪ Pray it away, I swear
I'll never be a saint, no way ♪
♪ My enemy ♪
♪ Pray it away, I swear
I'll never be a saint ♪
♪ Look out for yourself ♪
Noxus prizes strength
above all else,
defining it by three core principles.
Vision.
The top of the triangle.
Charting a course,
and having the wisdom to navigate it.
This form is your base, child.
Your eyes see what others don't.
Might.
Bending your environment to your will.
Your speed is improving.
But eventually you need force.
Too much force
exposes you to risk.
Indeed.
The last is guile.
Phantoms.
Tricksters.
Mages.
Absent honor.
Absent accountability.
Remember this, Caitlyn.
Tunnels in your eyes.
Lava in your veins.
Shadows in your heart.
This is the truth of combat.
I've discovered a fourth principle.
One that heightens all others.
Sacrifice.
The temper born of suffering.
We understand it as others cannot.
We are kin.
Pardon the interruption.
I've tracked him to Zaun.
Let's hunt a beast.
Vi.
I hoped you might return.
You filthy traitor.
Yes.
That was me at my worst.
Simply awful.
But the Herald has freed me
of my past self.
He's given me a chance to make amends.
- Excuse me. Some water?
- All are welcome.
But I must ask you
to surrender your weapons.
This is a place of peace.
Ugh.
Hm.
Welcome, you two.
Hello, friend.
Would you like some fruit?
The Herald's vision.
Come, he's expecting you.
We hear you can heal people.
Viktor.
You once told me, all systems have limits.
He is worth the risk.
Vander's psyche is
deeply entangled with that of the beast.
How did you know his name?
He told me.
Ask for a miracle healer,
get a metal fortune cookie.
I saw your father.
His dream of your family
and vision of Zaun as it could have been,
it was...
beautiful.
Cookie.
Can you help him?
I will do all in my power.
Hmm. Hmm?
However, I have one condition.
Looks like you got a couple.
You have much
to offer this commune, Powder.
Your talents can be used to build,
instead of destroy.
I'll stick with what I know, thanks.
My condition is that
he must be restrained at night.
I've seen the harm of which he is capable.
What do you think?
You actually want my opinion?
I hate fortune cookies.
We're gonna get you out of there, Vander.
♪ Can you find me? ♪
♪ I'm not hiding ♪
♪ All my memories ♪
♪ Aren't mine now ♪
♪ Not me ♪
♪ Show yourself ♪
♪ We're all creatures ♪
♪ Who am I to you? ♪
♪ Find the mirror ♪
♪ See what I see ♪
♪ Remember me ♪
♪ Remember me
I'm on my own ♪
I'm too far gone ♪
♪ I couldn't see ♪
♪ Remember me ♪
♪ Remember me... ♪
- My girls.
- Pow-Pow, come here.
♪ All my life, I couldn't breathe ♪
♪ Remember me ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
Do you remember them?
I remember Mom's smell the most.
- Axle grease.
This place.
Do you think it could actually work?
Underground utopia,
run by a skinny tin Machine Herald.
Maybe when Piltover slides into the sump.
What if we stayed?
Helped them out?
"We"?
Forward!
Halt.
No weapons.
I'm afraid the Herald insists.
If I may.
I believe this Herald may be
a former pupil of mine.
A man of science.
Let me speak with him.
Hmm.
Ready our forces for tonight.
I should like to meet this Herald.
You've felt it, haven't you?
Your decline?
Your power is finite,
diminished by every use.
I've been expecting you, doctor.
Viktor.
Incredible.
What I wouldn't give
to glimpse the world through your eyes.
To know what you know.
His quest led him astray
of any trodden path.
His own shadow dissolved to darkness.
Now the only course was forward.
The only warmth, a dream of her waltz.
Knowledge is a paradox.
The more one understands,
the more one realizes
the vastness of his ignorance.
Marvelous specimen, isn't he?
The regenerative qualities
of his blood will stabilize you.
Apex Shimmer combined with you,
the apex form of Hextech.
What you are suggesting would destroy him.
And for what?
Conquest?
The greed of warmongers?
To complete your work.
To save us from ourselves.
You must survive, Viktor.
Do you believe in fate, doctor?
Our paths carved before us.
Guided by an invisible hand?
Not fate, evolution.
Nature's greatest force, forever in flux.
No.
Evolution has a destination.
Not to combat nature,
but to supersede it.
The final, glorious evolution.
But he isn't a specimen.
He's a man.
And he needs my help.
I will not sacrifice his humanity
for your cause.
You may leave.
Very well.
But I assume you understand already,
if you perish,
this community is soon to follow.
On the job, I see.
You can't be here.
Oh. Here, like where I landed
when this rich, unhinged mongoose
just tackled me?
Mongoose?
Your hair.
You look like an angry oil slick.
Don't sugarcoat it, cupcake.
The routes in and out
of this canyon are being monitored.
No one can come in or out
without being questioned.
Who's out there?
We tracked some sort
of new chemweapon down here.
A bloodthirsty murderous beast.
What are you doing here?
Trying to save... my dad.
Viktor believes he can save
the man inside the beast.
If he succeeds, I'm afraid the creature's
usefulness will be lost to us.
Then we'll have to force his hand.
I believe I can craft a serum
that will prohibit Viktor's success.
Make sure it's secured.
Yes?
It's Vi.
So much for happy reunions.
Well done, Caitlyn.
It's time.
We have scouts up now, sir.
Six, collectively.
Slippery as an eel.
I knew you could get it.
Had some time to think lately.
Ever since you dropped into my life,
it's like I put on glasses.
Except I can't tell
whether everything's blurry or clear.
Wanna hear a dumb joke?
A sentimental ex-con, a giant furball,
and two of Piltover's most wanted
walk into a weird cult.
And here comes the punch line.
Vi.
You've been quite a curiosity.
One who captured Caitlyn's heart.
I owe you thanks.
Your absence provided a vacuum
I was able to fill.
In other circumstances, I might have
offered you a position in my organization.
Your resilience is undeniable.
Of course, that won't be possible.
You cause too many complications.
Caitlyn must not be distracted.
Don't worry, she's not distracted.
You know, my father taught me about trust.
He told me if I wanted it,
there were three things I needed to do:
Be honest, even if it means
telling a self-righteous windbag
that her breath smells like a cesspool.
Be patient.
Mm, still haven't cracked that one,
but being tied up sure helps.
And the third?
Just shut the fuck up.
The fissures are blocked by guard towers.
Patrols circle the commune
at even intervals.
Her personal guard are posted
here, here and here.
They aren't expecting trouble at home.
With flawless timing and luck and...
A big distraction.
Whatever you do,
don't underestimate Ambessa.
Vander's in trouble.
I have a plan.
You're not gonna like it.
Hope I was worth your time.
I won't...
I won't fail.
Vi sent me.
I'm going to get you out of here.
Ambessa believed in you.
Your death will be a deep cut.
Don't touch my daughter.
You.
I won't fail.
I swear it.
Vander.
I understand now.
The message hidden within the pattern.
The reason for our failures
in the commune.
The doctor was right.
It's inescapable.
Humanity.
Our very essence.
Our emotions...
Rage.
Compassion.
Hate.
Two sides of the same coin.
Inextricably bound.
Vander, wait.
Pew!
Boo!
No!
Pew!
Isha!
That which inspires us
to our greatest good...
is also the cause of our greatest evil.